Guide to the J. Archibald Murray Scrapbooks 1870s-1900 (bulk, 1893-1899 MS 3186
New-York Historical Society
J. Archibald Murray scrapbooks
1870s-1900 (bulk, 1893-1899)
New-York Historical Society
Murray, J. Archibald (John Archibald), 1857-1954
MS 3186
23 Linear feet in 23 record cartons (135 volumes + 1 envelope)
The collection holds 135 volumes of scrapbooks containing newspaper clippings. The bulk date from the 1890s. Most seem to be general news clippings, with some volumes having a thematic focus, principally "necrology."
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers. Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Arrangement
Although the scrapbooks as a whole have a thematic and chronological arrangement as set by Murray, the volumes are not sorted and boxed in any particular order.
Biographical / Historical
J. Archibald Murray (1857-1954) became a member of N-YHS in 1885 and held a position on its Executive Committee from 1913-1932. In the 1920s, he was also a Vice-President of the organization.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Five of the volumes were a gift from J. Archibald Murray on June 16, 1937. The dates of donation of the other volumes have not been determined.
Scope and Contents
The collection holds 135 volumes of scrapbooks containing newspaper clippings compiled by J. Archibald Murray. Perhaps most of the volumes have labels on the spines, but many have lost their labels (and the spine in some instances). This description is based largely on the labels; the contents of very few of the volumes were reviewed for this description. The bulk of the labels include the year (and sometimes month) of the clippings, with the general reference "newspaper cuttings" or "newspaper clippings." Some have volume numbers, but not all. At least eight of the volumes hold "necrology" (i.e., articles concerning deaths). Other small subsets are "Buffalo & Pittsfield" (articles from the press in those cities) and "Education, etc." Although the absence of labels limits the description in this note, there were single volumes labeled "Science & Fine Arts, 1896," "China & Japan," "Union College, 1895," and "Clippings from English papers."
The bulk of the volumes date from the 1890s, ending in 1900. At least one volume extends back to the 1870s, but its format differs somewhat from the other volumes and may have gotten included in the collection over time by mistake.
Newspaper clippings.; Scrapbooks.
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 1)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 2)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 3)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 4)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 5)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 6)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 7)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 8)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 9)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 10)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 11)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 12)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 13)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 14)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 15)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 16)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 17)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 18)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 19)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 20)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 21)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 22)
- Clippings scrapbooks, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 23)